Eric F. Garcia

Ashburn, VA 20148 (571) 357-0234

Ericg8251@gmail.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-f-garcia-a8130415

GitHub: https://ericgarcia38.github.io/efgp/

Nationality: French. Permanent US Resident / Green Card holder.

Senior Software Engineer and Project Manager

Technology-focused professional with broad based experience delivering on-time solutions and meaningful process improvements well prepared to significantly impact operations and profitability in a software engineering role.

Team-oriented leader with project management expertise leading strategic technology projects, including applications, software and hardware solutions. Develops and leverages internal and external relationships to maximize the achievement of business goals; ensures business and technology solutions are aligned, secure, and compliant with corporate strategies. Uses Agile and SCRUM methodologies to manage risk, control, and deliver quality, accurate product for the customer. Focuses on processes; review established processes, identify underperforming components, develop modifications and implement them across the organization. Values data; consistently measuring progress and performance through models, metrics, and research to inform project decisions.

Core Competencies:

Project Management	Data Analysis	Relationship Management	Industry Expertise
SCRUM/AgilePrioritization	BudgetingForecasting	Technical SupportVendor Management	BankingConsumerFinance
 Deliverable Management Software Development Life Cycle Data Migration 	Process ImprovementTechnology Implementation	NegotiationsProblem Solving	MortgageLeasingFleet Management

Technical Proficiencies

OS	IBM P6-7, AS-400, LINUX, WINDOWS SERVER
Software	CASSIOPAE, EVOLAN, Software Research, MIMIX
Languages	PL/SQL, SQL, RPG ILE , C,C#, C++, JAVA , DELPHI 1- 10.2 , Javascript
Frameworks	Sencha Ext Js, Jquery , Nodejs, Jasper Reports, LANSA

Eric F. Garcia

Professional Experience

Cassiopae US. Burlington, MA 2013 – 2019

Senior Engineer - LOAN/Leasing (Cassiopae) Oracle ,PL/SQL C++/ DELPHI- XE 10.3 , Jasper Report , JAVA , SOAP UI

Cassiopae is a Financial software for loans, leasing and mortgages created in Java Jzee connected to an Oracle DB, and defined in application service such as Weblogic, or Tomcat.

Collaborate with clients to clearly define the project scope, objectives, and success metrics;

I implement the settings based on the Business requirements with Sql.

I follow up, debug, monitor, and install the application on the client side.

I debug and analyze the weblogic logs, to solve customer problems as quickly as possible.

I debug and modify the SOAP Cassiopae web services with tools such as SOAPUI.

I modify if possible the JAVA programs or put back my expertise towards the site of research and development in Paris. All the changes are managed under Svn and the trace in Jira.

I create and modify the Plsql functions, packages etc.. according to the client's needs.

I build the Jasper reports and PI Sql functions linked to .

I manage and create the sql, scripts and Plsql program for the data migration between the legacy DB and the target Cassiopae. I create the shell Unix to create batches to incorporate in the Jenkins processes.

Furthermore, I created the business requirements, mockups, and worked on the project of management of delivery SQL scripts through Oracle which have to be linked to a Bank software. The general requirement was to share a place where all the consultants have to enter their own scripts, and then to manage the Master script in a DEVOPS environment. (connected to git, jenkins and Jira).

The project was developed with Delphi XE₅ and migrated to XE₈ as a Web application, with Ajax requests technologies and a Front End built with the framework Sencha Ext/Js.

Societe Generale Consumer Finance. Paris, France, 2006 – 2012

Country Manager for Consumer Loan on ISERIES (SOPRA EVOLAN), RPG ILE ,

Selected Projects & Achievements:

• Lead and develop a project to downsize hardware and software utilization for a mid-sized organization; after implementation the customer costs fell almost \$4 million annually. For the security

- connections I Developed an emulation 5250 for Iseries/As400 with securities keywords, in order to cover the security and trace of connections to the mainframe.
- The software was developed in **DELPHI 2007** for the 5250 Emulation and **DELPHI XE2** and **BUilder C++** for the Database security management as an intranet WEB application, all connected to a DB2/400 server program written in **RPG ILE** and **CLLE**.

Crédit Immobilier EST. Metz, Strasbourg, France, 2004 – 2006

Consultant - IBM for Mortgage Migration UNIX Progress to ISERIES Db2/400,

Consultant and project manager, for a data migration project from Unix Progress tools (VINCI software to an AS400 database Finance Software)

- To create the Interfaces between the business teams.
- Management of the project.
- Creation of programs to upload the data into DB2. /400 13500 mortgages (**Rpg ILE, CLLE, DELPHI 2007**)

President GDB SYSTEMS GRENOBLE, France, 2002 – 2004

PM and SENIOR ISERIES Engineer and C++/ DELPHI DEVELOPER,

Acting as President of the company GDB-SYSTEMS, I was commissioned as Project Manager for BNP Bank, to work on the new arrangements for EBICS banking transfers in Europe. This solution had to run on a Windows station connected to an IBM AS400 (DB2). The solution has been developed around **DELPHI7** and **RPG-ILE for ISERIES.**

EASII, Rhône Alpes, France, 1992 – 2002. CTO,

- Creation of a tool box ACTIVEX for companies as ASNA (TX San Antonio) and LANSA ASPECT COMPUTING (Australia, Sydney) to connect in native mod (no SQL) to DB2 400.
- The development was done with DELPHI 1till DELPHI 6.

Education

Master of Science, Enterprise Data Processing (1987) CNAM of GRENOBLE, Grenoble, France

Eric F. Garcia

Bachelor of Science, Statistics (1981) IUT GRENOBLE II, Grenoble, France

Certifications

IBM P6-7, AS-400, Windows Servers, Oracle PL/SQL

Nationality

French. Permanent US Resident / Green Card holder.